A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of David Bell FA624
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Appendix A: Reports Accessioned
  - Barber, Elinor. International programs related to the status, roles, and opportunities of women, 1975 August (Report 2066)
  - Ford Foundation. International Urbanization Survey - findings and recommendations, 1971 (Report 5838)
  - Peterson, Maurice L. An International Water Management Institute, a prospectus, 1970 March (Report 4020)
  - Kennedy/Hagler. Investment policies, spending policies, and uncertainty, 1977 June (Report 3287)
  - Goodwin/Silj. Ireland, 1972 June (Report 9044)
  - Rudlin, Walter. Israel, 1957 August (Report 8136)
  - Hill, F.F. Issues in establishing an Overseas Development program in Afghan1stan: a summary, n.d. (Report 148)
  - Bell, David E. Items for the Foundation's "Planning, exploration, and evaluation agenda", 1972 February (Report 2462)
  - Dye, Richard W. The Jakarta Faculty of Economics, 1965 January (Report 374)
  - Geertz, Clifford. The judging of nations: some comments on the assessment of regimes in the new states, 1975 September (Report 2919)
  - Finkelstein, David. (Korea), 1975 June (Report 2044)
  - Gaitskell, Arthur. (Land problems and reform), 1961 October (Report 8902)
  - Hardin, Lowell S. Later-generation agricultural development problems, 1969 (Report 6988)
  - Hill, F. F. Locating the key log in the jam: the problem of priorities in agricultural development, 1969 (Report 1396)
  - Heaps, David. The Maghreb, 1968 January (Report 8907)
  - Hungate, Jess. Malaysia summary, 1974 September (Report 9051)
  - Dye, Richard W. Malaysian foreign policy - the Southeast Asia region, 1970 February (Report 3793)
  - Silva/Strasburg. Malnutrition in Latin America; recommendations for Ford Foundation support of research and training in human nutrition, 1970 October (Report 3814)
  - Robinson/Swearer. Management education in Europe, 1969 December (Report 5182)
  - Doran, Ron. Management review report - New Delhi field office, 1977 April (Report 9079)
  - Howe, Harold. Material from EPP re Women's Programs - in response to your January 18 memo, 1980 January (Report 8938)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Meeting in Ireland, January 5-6, 1973 January (Report 9045)
  - Goodyear/Mayer. Meeting Nov. 23, 1971: (4 issues papers), 1971 November (Report 8831)
  - Gant, George F. Meeting of representatives, South and Southeast Asia program, New Delhi, Feb. 15-16, 1963, 1963 March (Report 9085)
  - Gant, George F. Meeting of representatives, South and Southeast Asia program, Kuala Lumpur, Jan. 13-14, 1964, 1964 February (Report 9086)
  - Heard/Bundy. Memorandum for the Trustees re: Board's Future Program Planning Project, 1975 December (Report 9180)
  - Ford Foundation. Memorandum to the International Committee, Board of Trustees, 1974 March (Report 9099)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Merrimon Cunningim' s work and our response -- a summary report, 1975 June (Report 9185)
  - Ford Foundation. Metropolitan Opera Association - Arts Committee meeting, June 29-30, 1978, 1978 June (Report 4840)
  - Ford Foundation. Middle East - Africa program, 1966 December (Report 2849)
  - Kingsley, J. Donald. The Middle East-Africa Program - summary report at end of Fiscal Year 1964, 1964 October (Report 9019)
  - Robinson, Pearl T. The Middle East and Africa Field Research Fellowship Program for Afro-Americans, 1975 July (Report 9022)
  - Ford Foundation. Middle East program plans, 1976 March (Report 9210)
  - Scott, Thomas D. Middle East Studies, Dr. Heard's enquiry, 1973 June (Report 8905)
  - Frodin/Morrill. Mission report -- University of Chile, June 19 - July 8, 1963, 1963 August (Report 10)
  - Bresnan, John. Mr. Bhutto's Pakistan, 1976 April (Report 9109)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. A modified schedule for program planning and budgeting, 1972 January (Report 5860)
  - (Nelson, Courtney A.) Musings on the Middle East program, 1976 (Report 3130)
  - Smock, David R. My trip to East Africa - August 8-26, 1968, 1968 September (Report 4832)
  - Ford Foundation. National affairs program priorities in the coming years, 1978 October (Report 6509)
  - Smock, David R. National integration in West Africa, 1971 September (Report 3976)
  - Ford Foundation. New opportunities for the Foundation in Nicaragua, 1979 December (Report 9000)
  - Ford Foundation. Next steps for the Foundation concerning China, 1979 June (Report 4112)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Next steps on the Trustees' Future Program Planning Project, 1976 September (Report 9206)
  - Bell, David E. Next steps regarding the Division's program for women, 1980 January (Report 5697)
  - Bell, David E. Next steps regarding the Division's program in population, 1980 January (Report 7060)
  - Kingsley, J. Donald. Nigeria - Ghana program summary and outlook for fiscal 1963, 1962 August (Report 8915)
  - Korbonski, Andrzej. Non-Russian nationalities in the USSR, 1970 October (Report 9037)
  - Staples, Eugene S. A note on Asia, 1970 March (Report 5117)
  - Wilhelm, Harry E. A note on India, 1975 September (Report 4925)
  - Staples, Eugene S. A note on Indonesia and Malaysia, 1969 November (Report 9092)
  - Staples, Eugene S. A note on Southeast Asia: Vietnam and the Philippines, 1973 March (Report 9093)
  - Staples, Eugene S. A note on Vietnam and Southeast Asia, 1968 September (Report 9090)
  - Staples, Eugene S. Notes on East and Southeast Asia and India, 1969 September (Report 9091)
  - Ford Foundation. Notes on Indonesia and Burma, 1961 January (Report 376)
  - Marshall, Dorothy. Notes on June 1975 tr1p to Latin America, 1975 July (Report 8974)
  - Hathaway, Dale E. Notes on the world food situation, 1974 August (Report 9200)
  - (Hill, F. F.) Notes on the world's food problem, 1966 April (Report 8899)
  - Kennedy, Roger P. Object1ves, risk and policy, 1975 December (Report 2880)
  - Ensminger, Douglas. (Observations on India's needs to successfully complete the Five-Year Plan), 1953 April (Report 3357)
  - Hardin, Lowell. Observations on the food situation based on visits in Africa and Asia, April 26 - June 6, 1974, 1974 June (Report 9197)
  - Gant, George. OD policies - a discussion outline, 1967 (Report 9014)
  - Ford Foundation. OD Program - agricultural research and the Ford Foundation, a discussion paper, 1966 August (Report 5000)
  - Heaps, David. OD Self-Study. Lagos, 1966 September (Report 2406)
  - Gamble, William K. OD Self-Study - Mexico, 1966 September (Report 3055)
  - Dye, Richard. OD Self-Study - questions for representatives (Malaysia - Singapore), 1966 (Report 3069)
  - Crawley, Roy W. OD Self-Study - questions for representatives. The Ford Foundation - report for Venezuela, 1966 September (Report 3056)
  - Hanson, Haldore et al. OD Self-Study series - Pakistan Program, Ford Foundation 1952 - 1966, 1966 October (Report 3070)
  - Ford Foundation. OD Self-Study. I. A summary of replies from representatives. II. A summary of replies from non-Foundation respondents, 1966 December (Report 2714)
  - (Simons, Hans). ODLA activities in Higher Education, 1966 September (Report 8952)
  - Nagel, John S. Office for Latin America and the Caribbean, report on FY 1970, 1970 December (Report 8925)
  - Ford Foundation. Office of Latin America and the Caribbean. Population and family planning in Mexico, 1978 July (Report 8960)
  - Ford Foundation. On managing risk, 1975 September (Report 2736)
  - Sutton, F. X. Operation Janus - East Africa: Kenya, 1966 (Report 3059)
  - Sutton, F. X. Operation Janus - general replies, 1966 (Report 3061)
  - Sutton, F. X. Operation Janus - other countries, 1966 (Report 3060)
  - Bell, David E. Organization of the International Division for dealing with Europe and the Far East, 1968 May (Report 9042)
  - Ford Foundation. Our finances and our future, 1974 September (Report 9201)
  - Ford Foundation. Our finances and our future revisited, 1974 December (Report 9192)
  - Shaw, Robert D'Arcy. Outline for a possible Foundation program in Pakistan, 1980 May (Report 9101)
  - Himes. James R. Overseas Administrative Conference, Mt. Kenya, July 7-10, 1969, 1969 July (Report 9021)
  - Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program - evaluation (1951 - 1961) and statement of current objectives and policies, 1961 December (Report 8897)
  - Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program: IITA located in Nigeria, 1966 March (Report 2812)
  - Ford Foundation. Overseas Development Program: proposal for an International Institute of Tropical Agriculture located in Africa, 1963 December (Report 2859)
  - Shaw, Robert D'Arcy. Pakistan and the Ford Foundation, 1979 December (Report 9001)
  - Edwards, Robert H. Pakistan, March 1980., 1980 April (Report 7116)
  - Bell, David E. Pending tax legislation affecting the Foundation's activities, 1969 June (Report 8833)
  - Bell, David E. Pending tax legislation affecting the Foundation's activities (Chapter 2), 1969 September (Report 8834)
  - McCaughey, Robert A. The permanent revolution: an assessment of the current state of International Studies in American universities, 1979 January (Report 5093)
  - Larsen, Roy E. Personnel for overseas development, 1962 December (Report 824)
  - Gant, George F. Personnel for overseas development, 1962 December (Report 3439)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Perspectives of the International Division on program activities bearing on the status of women, 1972 May (Report 7750)
  - Ford Foundation/Trustees Philanthropic choices, style and methods: a 25-year review, 1976 (Report 2738)
  - Staples, Eugene S. The Philippines, 1969 March (Report 8966)
  - Staples, Eugene S. Philippines, 1970 December (Report 8967)
  - Bresnan, John. The Philippines, 1976 February (Report 8968)
  - Ford Foundation. Planning for the Foundation's activities in Europe, 1967 December (Report 2122)
  - Ford Foundation. Planning for the Foundation's program in 1973 and beyond, 1972 March (Report 2450)
  - Ward, F. C. Plans and resources of other agencies for assisting educational development in the seventies and their possible implications for the International Division (Report 8933)
  - Ward, F. C. Policy paper - population, 1963 (Report 2856)
  - Sutton/Goodwin. Policy studies in Europe, 1977 June (Report 9023)
  - Esman, Milton J. Political and administrative dimensions of ethnic conflict in Malaysia, 1970 February (Report 3795)
  - Morse, Richard et al. Political and economic profile of Colombia - Ford Foundation mission to Colombia, June 1960 (Report 323)
  - Mayer, Robert A. The political situation in the Dominican Republic, 1965 September (Report 8955)
  - Saunders, Lyle. Population, development, and applied social science: a conference report, 1978 May (Report 3756)
  - Ford Foundation. Population in the 1980s - information paper, 1979 December (Report 4640)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Population Office activities, fiscal 1968, 1969 January (Report 7819)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Population Office activities, fiscal 1969, 1970 January (Report 7820)
  - Ford Foundation. A portfolio of large scale possibilities, 1971 June (Report 2858)
  - Silvert, Kalman H. Possible Foundation activities involving Cuban affairs, 1967 October (Report 8954)
  - Coombs, Philip H. et al. The preparation of teachers in Turkey, 1957 December (Report 3621)
  - Heald, Henry T. Private American cooperation with Asia, 1957 (Report 3159)
  - Ginsburg/Dressner. Private foundations and governmental attitudes: 1985, 1976 (Report 6580)
  - Hill, F. F. Private foundations and organizations, 1964 (Report 4084)
  - Duarte, Rodrigo et al. Private technical assistance in agricultural development: the Colombia model, 1969 June (Report 8986)
  - Ford Foundation. Problems and opportunities in governance and economics: two discussion papers for the Board of Trustees, 1979 March (Report 4119)
  - Hanson, Haldore. Problems facing the Nigerian Federal Government during 1970, and assistance from the Ford Foundation, 1970 January (Report 8916)
  - Bell, David E. Program exploration: H/N/P in developing countries, 1979 August (Report 7141)
  - Mayer, Robert A. Program management trends that cause increased demand for management services, 1967 September (Report 8829)
  - Ford Foundation. The program of transitional support to International Studies in American universities, 1969 December (Report 2861)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Program on the future of the International Economic Order, 1976 February (Report 8845)
  - Ford Foundation. Program opportunities in Zimbabwe?, 1980 March (Report 9003)
  - Jones, Sidney. Program plans and initial budget for expanded women's activities, 1980 January (Report 9110)
  - Schaller, Howard G. Program trends and planning, 1972 April (Report 9103)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Progress report and recommendations for future activities concerning the International Economic Order, 1975 June (Report 8844)
  - Ford Foundation. ID/POP. Progress report: review of research and funding in reproductive biology and contraceptive development, 1974 March (Report 9195)
  - Doggett, Hugh et al. Proposal for an International Crops Research Institute for the Semi-Arid Tropics (ICRISAT), 1971 October (Report 4801)
  - Ford Foundation. Proposals for Trustee consideration: two research library grants from General Reserve funds, 1978 June (Report 4132)
  - Ford Foundation. Proposed FY 1981 management costs budgets, 1980 September (Report 8850)
  - Teitelbaum, Michael S. A proposed Foundation-wide program on immigration and refugees, 1979 November (Report 8837)
  - Ward, F. C. Prospective developmental needs overseas and the evaluation of OD, 1966 April (Report 8900)
  - Hathaway, Dale E. A prospectus for the International Food Policy Research Institute, 1975 April (Report 9007)
  - Ford Foundation/R&E. Public policy analysis: the Brookings Institution and Resources for the Future - a grant request and discussion paper, 1978 June (Report 4147)
  - Ford Foundation. Public Policy and Social Organization: proposed program and budget for FY 1980 and FY 1981 (Report 9113)
  - Heaps, David. Quebec - Canada, 1972 August (Report 9031)
  - Gardner, James A. A question of values, 1976 December (Report 7559)
  - Shaw, Robert D'Arcy. Recent events in Pakistan, 1979 December (Report 7103)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Recent travels, 1972 May (Report 9025)
  - Jones, Ronald W. Recommendations on evaluation of M-E-C program, 1953 September (Report 8457)
  - Sutton, F. X. Reflections on a visit in Japan, October 1968, 1969 January (Report 9080)
  - Finkelstein, David. Reflections on China, 1975 September (Report 4080)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Remarks to the staff of the Ford Foundation by McGeorge Bundy, 1974 September (Report 9194)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Remarks to the staff of the Ford Foundation by McGeorge Bundy, 1974 December (Report 9193)
  - Himes, James R. Renewed program and budget review (Dick Dye's memo of 4/25/14), 1974 May (Report 8999)
  - (Faust, Clarence). Report of a meeting on university projects under Ford Foundation grants in South and South-east Asia, Dec. 7, 1959 (Report 9084)
  - Brown, William et al. Report of Ford Foundation mission to Africa, 1957 January (Report 579)
  - Everton, John Scott. Report of Ford Foundation mission to Japan, 1957 May (Report 2660)
  - Bell, David E. et al. Report of the Committee to Study Experience of the Harvard-Pakistan Planning Commission Project, 1962 March (Report 368)
  - Millett, John D. et al. Report of the Ford Foundation mission to Mexico, November - December 1961 (Report 36)
  - Fox, John B. et al. Report of the Fox-Robinson mission regarding the advisability of furthering education in business administration in Turkey, 1953 June (Report 588)
  - Ford Foundation. Report of the Subcommittee on Affirmative Action, 1975 December (Report 3129)
  - Ford Foundation. Report of the Trustees Ad Hoc Committee on the Overseas Development Program, presented at the meeting, March 28/29, 1963 (Report 8896)
  - Ford Foundation. Report on an exploration of grant-making possibilities in Vietnam, 1974 March (Report 2434)
  - Ames, Edward A. Report on European discussions, 1972 June (Report 8852)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Report on Henry Ford Hospital, 1976 September (Report 9205)
  - Curtis, Gerald L. Report on Japan related programs, 1971 (Report 9081)
  - Smock, David R. Report on my trip to South Africa, 1969 March (Report 8908)
  - Dye, Richard W. Report on my visit to Chile -- March 20 - 23, 1974 March (Report 8958)
  - Staples, Eugene S. A report on our thinking about East Asia, 1970 January (Report 5099)
  - Ford Foundation. A report on Program-Related Investments, 1977 June (Report 4120)
  - Heaps, David. Report on refugee situation in Botswana, 1977 June (Report 4558)
  - Davidson, Carter et al. Report on Robert College and the American College for Girls, Istanbul, Turkey, 1957 December (Report 8895)
  - Gant, George F. Report on South and Southeast Asia program FY1958 - 59, 1960 January (Report 8459)
  - Heaps, David. Report on West Africa, 1972 April (Report 8917)
  - Bell, David E. Request for funding from FY 1980 General Reserves, International Division, 1980 February (Report 8965)
  - Hawkins, Robert G. Research priorities concerning multinational firms and foreign direct investment: the economic issues, 1977 May (Report 8842)
  - Ford Foundation. Resources and the environment in the developing countries, 1976 March (Report 9208)
  - Ford Foundation. Resources for the Future: a review, 1976 September (Report 3471)
  - Bell, David E. Retrenchment of management costs, 1975 February (Report 8998)
  - Ford Foundation. Retrenchment of management costs: a progress report, 1975 March (Report 9184)
  - Newmann, John M. Review of economics in Asia: what have we learned?, 1976 (Report 3304)
  - Ginsburg, Benson E. Review of Ford Foundation program in Israel and Turkey, 1961 May (Report 359)
  - Bell, Peter D. Review of the Foundation's program in Chile and staff deployment for the Southern Cone, 1974 April (Report 8951)
  - Ford Foundation. A review of the problem of personnel for overseas development - progress report, 1962 September (Report 8898)
  - Ford Foundation. (Revised) special guidelines on the legal framework for grants to foreign organizations, 1974 December (Report 8836)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Royaumont conference on the role of the economist in government, 1974 May (Report 9047)
  - Ford Foundation. Safeguarding rights and welfare of human subjects in biomedical research supported by the Ford Foundation, 1972 November (Report 2131)
  - Aresvik, Oddvar. Selected agricultural statistics in ranked order for countries of the Near East Region, 1972 September (Report 3611)
  - Matlon, Peter. Selected notes on RFF study of Middle Eastern agricultural potential, 1971 April (Report 5150)
  - Chafkin, Sol H. Significant, complicated, neglected: the nutrition factor affecting Foundation programs, 1979 May (Report 4200)
  - Sutton, F. X. The situation in East and Central Africa and outlines of a Foundation program there, 1965 April (Report 3608)
  - Soedjatmoko. The social challenge to modern architecture -- the Aga Khan award for architecture in the spirit of Islam, 1980 October (Report 8849)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Social research and population policy: summary and recommendations, 1973 March (Report 5029)
  - (Kiene, Werner.) Social science research and rural development, 1975 April (Report 4927)
  - Smock, David R. Social science research in South Africa, 1974 December (Report 8911)
  - Sutton, F. X. Social values and culture in the modern world, 1975 December (Report 3090)
  - Staples, Eugene S. Some observations on Indonesia, 1967 September (Report 9070)
  - Wald, Patricia. Some observations on the survival of children around the world, 1974 August (Report 6302)
  - Swearer, Howard R. Some points of view about the Foundation's Polish program, 1967 December (Report 9035)
  - Dye, Richard W. Some principal issues in Ford Foundation program management, 1973 September (Report 2116)
  - Wald, Patricia. Some reactions from my trip (July 5 - August 10) to Niger, Nigeria, South Africa, Kenya, India, Thailand, South Vietnam, Japan, 1974 September (Report 5836)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Some reflections on the social sciences and the Soedjatmoko problem, 1976 June (Report 9117)
  - Soedjatmoko. ("South-South Dialogue" in Arusha, Tanzania), 1979 January (Report 5561)
  - Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia, 1967 June (Report 2407)
  - Gant, George F. The South and Southeast Asia program in FY 1960-61, 1961 December (Report 8460)
  - Gant, George F. The South and Southeast Asia program in FY 1963, 1963 December (Report 9087)
  - Gant, George F. The South and Southeast Asia program for FY 1963-64, 1964 December (Report 9088)
  - Miller, Frank J. The South and Southeast Asia program for FY 1964 - 1965, 1965 December (Report 9089)
  - Ford Foundation. South and Southeast Asia Program - possible Ford Foundation activity in Thailand - discussion paper, 1965 (Report 9101)
  - Ford Foundation. Southeast Asia after Vietnam, 1975 June (Report 6419)
  - Fredericks, Wayne. Southern Africa, 1972 February (Report 5996)
  - Edwards, Robert H. Southern Africa: program directions, 1977 June (Report 7409)
  - Lederer, Ivo J. Soviet academic emigres, 1975 April (Report 9039)
  - Ford Foundation (Special Committee) Program concerning future program activities: Overseas Development (including South and Southeast Asia, Near East and Africa, Latin America and the Caribbean), 1962 Spring (Report 3096)
  - Ford Foundation (Special Committee.) Program submission concerning future program activities: International Affairs, 1962 Spring (Report 3092)
  - Dressner, Howard R. Special guidelines on the legal framework for grants to foreign organizations, 1973 January (Report 8835)
  - Hardin, Lowell et al. Special paper. Notes on program strategies which seek to advance the welfare of the rural poor, 1979 January (Report 5868)
  - Sommer, John G. Sri Lanka - another Ford Foundation, 1974 January (Report 9083)
  - Smock, David R. Staff development at South Africa's black universities, 1974 December (Report 8912)
  - Ford Foundation/Trustees Staff responses to Alexander Heard's September 24 memorandum, "Next steps in planning for the Foundation's future", vol. I, 1976 November (Report 6591)
  - Ward, F. C. State of play in "international education" as of August 11, 1977 August (Report 8934)
  - Ward, F. C. State of play in "international education" as of September 6, 1977 September (Report 8932)
  - Nicholls, William H. The status of agricultural economics in Brazil - an appraisal with recommendations, 1960 August (Report 226)
  - Dye, Richard W. Status of international assistance to Latin America and other regions and implications for OLAC, 1973 September (Report 5906)
  - Fredericks, Wayne. Status report on the Foundation's activities concerning Southern Africa, 1972 June (Report 8910)
  - Southam/Harkavy. Status report: reproductive biology, 1969 September (Report 4853)
  - Ward, F. C. Sub-regions and sub-regional programs in the Middle East and Tropical Africa, 1963 February (Report 9018)
  - Dobbs, Frederick E. Suggestions and recommendations pertaining to the establishment of a Polytechnic Institute, 1952 April (Report 9105)
  - Seckler, David. Sukhomajri: a rural development program in India, 1980 (Report 6665)
  - Bell, David E. Summary comments: Bellagio IV Meeting on Population, Ulvshale, Denmark, June 9, 1977 (Report 9120)
  - Hardin, Lowell S. Summary of our observations and program suggestions, Middle East and North Africa, 1978 March (Report 5877)
  - Deutch, John et al. A summary of the evaluation of the Energy Policy Project, 1975 September (Report 6648)
  - Nielsen, Waldemar A. Summary report on present and possible future Foundation activities in Spain, 1968 January (Report 9024)
  - Ford Foundation/ID. Summary tables -- FY 1973 and earlier years, 1974 May 15 (Report 6248)